A Guide to the Peter Mellette Papers, 1945-1993
Library of Virginia
- Series III. NCCJ outreach and program file, 1946-1988., Extent: 27 boxes. (Box 18-44)
  - Brotherhood Weeks 1980, 1982 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Brotherhood Week, undated (Box 28, Folder 7-9)
  - Case Examples of Successful Regional Programming, 1969-1970 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Case Examples of Successful Regional Programming, 1970-1971 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Case Examples of Successful Regional Programming, 1972-1973 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Charles Evans Hughes Award (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Dialogue groups - Peninsula, Norfolk (Box 28, Folder 14-15)
  - Dialogue groups - Richmond (Box 29, Folder 1-4)
  - Educational films (advertisements, lists, etc.) (Box 29, Folder 5-6)
  - Educational literature and resource lists (Box 29, Folder 7-8)
  - Educational plays and skits (scripts) (Box 29, Folder 9-10)
  - Good Neighbor Awards, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Human relations programs and literature, 1946-1948 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Human relations programs and literature, 1950-1952 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Human relations programs and literature, 1953 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Human relations programs and literature, 1954 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Human relations programs and literature, 1955 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Human relations programs and literature, 1956-1957 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Human relations programs and literature, 1960-1964 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Human relations programs and literature, 1965-1968 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Human relations programs and literature, 1969 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Human relations programs and literature, 1970-1976 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Human relations programs and literature, undated (Box 31, Folder 2-4)
  - Labor-Management / Equal Employment Opportunity, 1951-1952 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Labor-Management / Equal Employment Opportunity, 1953-1954 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Labor-Management / Equal Employment Opportunity, 1956-1959 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Labor-Management / Equal Employment Opportunity, 1960-1963 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Labor-Management / Equal Employment Opportunity, 1964-1967 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Labor-Management / Equal Employment Opportunity, 1968-1969 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Labor-Management / Equal Employment Opportunity, 1970-1977 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Labor-Management / Equal Employment Opportunity, undated (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous NCCJ awards, 1953-1959 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous NCCJ awards, 1961-1966 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous NCCJ awards, 1967-1969 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous NCCJ awards, 1970-1974 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous NCCJ awards, 1976-1981 and undated (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous NCCJ programs, 1948-1959 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous NCCJ programs, 1962-1969 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous NCCJ programs, 1970-1978 and undated (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Moral and Spiritual Resources Project, 1953, 1956 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - NCCJ annual/program reports, 1950-1954 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - NCCJ annual/program reports, 1955-1957 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - NCCJ annual/program reports, 1958-1959 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - NCCJ annual/program reports, 1960-1967 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - NCCJ annual/program reports, 1968 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - NCCJ annual/program reports, 1969 (Box 33, Folder 5-6)
  - NCCJ annual/program reports, 1970-1978 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - NCCJ annual/program reports, 1981-1987 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - NCCJ program director diaries, February 1976 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - NCCJ Program Manual: Policy (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - NCCJ program planning, 1950's-1960's (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - NCCJ program planning, 1970's and undated (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - NCCJ program planning resources (Box 34, Folder 4-5)
  - Police-Community Relations, 1955 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Police-Community Relations, 1956-1959 (Box 34, Folder 7-8)
  - Police-Community Relations, 1960 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Police-Community Relations, 1961 (Box 35, Folder 1-2)
  - Police-Community Relations, 1962 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Police-Community Relations, 1963 (Box 35, Folder 4-5)
  - Police-Community Relations, 1964-1965 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Police-Community Relations, 1966 (Box 35, Folder 7-8)
  - Police-Community Relations, 1967 (Box 35, Folder 9-10)
  - Police-Community Relations, 1968 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Police-Community Relations, 1969 (Box 36, Folder 2-4)
  - Police-Community Relations, 1970 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Police-Community Relations, 1971 (Box 36, Folder 6-7)
  - Police-Community Relations, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Police-Community Relations, 1973-1977, 1980, 1982 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Police-Community Relations, undated (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Police-Community Relations, undated, cont'd. (Box 37, Folder 1-3)
  - Radio and television (Box 37, Folder 4-5)
  - Radio and television: Brotherhood at Work (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Radio and television: Human relations programming, WLVA-TV Lynchburg, 1960-1963 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Radio and television: Miscellaneous scripts (Box 37, Folder 8-9)
  - Radio and television: The Moral Challenge transcripts, 1960 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Radio and television: New Horizons in Human Relations, 1955 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Radio and television: New Horizons in Human Relations, 1955, cont'd. (Box 38, Folder 1-2)
  - Radio and television: New Horizons in Human Relations: A Thirteen Week Television Series, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Radio and television: Operation Understanding, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 4-5)
  - Rearing Children of Good Will, 1954-1959 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Rearing Children of Good Will, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Rearing Children of Good Will, 1961-1963 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Rearing Children of Good Will, 1964 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Rearing Children of Good Will, 1965 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Rearing Children of Good Will, 1966 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Rearing Children of Good Will, 1967 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Rearing Children of Good Will, 1968-1969 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Rearing Children of Good Will, 1970-1971, 1975-1976 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Rearing Children of Good Will, undated (Box 39, Folder 5-6)
  - Rearing Children of Good Will: Promising Practices in Rearing Children of Good Will (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Rearing Children of Good Will series discussion guides (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Rearing Children of Good Will: A Study and Discussion Guide for Parents (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Rearing Children of Good Will: A Thirteen Week Television Series (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Religious Freedom and Public Affairs (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Religious Freedom and Public Affairs, cont'd. (Box 40, Folder 1-7)
  - Religious News Service (Box 40, Folder 8-10)
  - Wildacres Institute on Human Relations, 1954-1956 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Wildacres Institute on Human Relations, 1957-1960 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Wildacres Institute on Human Relations, 1966-1967 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Wildacres Institute on Human Relations, 1968-1969 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Wildacres Institute on Human Relations, 1970 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Wildacres Institute on Human Relations, 1971, 1976 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Youth programs, 1940's (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Youth programs, 1950-1951 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Youth programs, 1952 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Youth programs, 1953 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Youth programs, 1954-1955 (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Youth programs, 1956 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Youth programs, 1957 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Youth programs, 1958-1959 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Youth programs, 1960 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Youth programs, 1961 (Box 42, Folder 5-6)
  - Youth programs, 1962 (Box 42, Folder 7-8)
  - Youth programs, 1963 (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Youth programs, 1963, cont'd. (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Youth programs, 1964 (Box 43, Folder 2-3)
  - Youth programs, 1965 (Box 43, Folder 4-5)
  - Youth programs, 1966 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Youth programs, 1967 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Youth programs, 1968 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Youth programs, 1969 (Box 43, Folder 9-10)
  - Youth programs, 1970 (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Youth programs (Ruth Blair files), 1970-1973 (Box 44, Folder 1-2)
  - Youth programs, 1971 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Youth programs, 1972 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Youth programs, 1973 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Youth programs, 1974 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Youth programs, 1975 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Youth programs, 1976 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Youth programs, 1977 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Youth programs, undated (Box 44, Folder 10-12)
- Series IV. Subject files, 1941-1993., Extent: 22 boxes. (Box 45-65, 78)
  Subject files reflect Peter Mellette's interests in religion, race relations, education, ethics, Richmond, and various other topics. Materials gathered here include correspondence, newsletters, informational literature, programs, clippings, partial drafts of Mellette's memoirs (a full version of which, entitled Some of Life's Moments, are in the collection of the Virginia Historical Society in Richmond), miscellaneous coursework from Mellette's graduate studies, and speeches. The speech files chiefly consist of printed copies of speeches made by other individuals, including Adlai Stevenson, Admiral Lewis L. Strauss, Eugene McCarthy, J. Edgar Hoover, Henry R. Luce, Chief Justice Earl Warren, Arthur Ashe, Judge Robert R. Merhige Jr., Henry Ford II, Lee Iacocca, and various NCCJ figures. Also included are a number of unsigned drafts of speeches that were likely Mellette's own.
  Arranged alphabetically by folder title. Note that the entry for "Miscellaneous objects" is listed here in alphabetical order, but the box itself (Box 78) is filed at the end of the collection because of its odd size.
  - 102 True Stories from the Greater St. Louis Community Chest, 1953 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Abortion (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Adult Leadership Training, Virginia State College (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Agency Professionals of Richmond (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - American Jewish Committee (Box 45, Folder 5-6)
  - American Shores Patrol (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Anti-Semitism (Box 45, Folder 8-9)
  - Anytown USA (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Appointment calendars, 1963, 1970-1974 (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Appointment calendars, 1975-1979 (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Arab-Israeli conflicts (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Arab-Israeli conflicts, cont'd. (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Attacks on the NCCJ (Box 46, Folder 2-3)
  - Better Business Bureau (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Biographical info and c.v.'s on various individuals (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Black-Jewish relations (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - B'nai B'rith (Box 46, Folder 7-9)
  - Book lists (Box 46, Folder 10-11)
  - Books for Brotherhood (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Brown, G. W. C. (Norfolk Division, Virginia State College) (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Building for Brotherhood (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Bulletin of Temple Beth-El (Richmond, Va.), 1958-1972 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Canada-United States Friendship Committee (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Catholic: Clergy (Richmond) (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Catholic: Miscellaneous (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Catholic: Vatican II (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Christian Science (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Christian Yellow Pages (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Church-State issues (Box 47, Folder 10-12)
  - Citizens' Community Study (Richmond, Va.), ca. 1972-1973 (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Civil Rights Act of 1964 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Civil rights/race relations/African American issues (Box 48, Folder 2-7)
  - Clinchy, Everett R. (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Colgate Divinity School (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Commission on Human Relations (Richmond, Va.) (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Communism (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Comparative Cultures and World Community course (Oberlin College), 1950 (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Congregation Beth Ahabah (Richmond, Va.) (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Constants and Variables in Southern Culture, Gordon Lovejoy, 1954 (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - Crozer Theological Seminary (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Crucifixion debate (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - The Curricular Approach to Religious Prejudice, J. Howard Howson, 1945 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Declaration of Moral Principles for General Assembly candidates, 1967 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Draft statement re: Martin Luther King assasination, 1968 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Drugs (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Ecumenical Social Concerns Alliance / VISCA (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Emergency School Assistance Advisory Committee (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Fair campaigns (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Fair campaigns: Presidential election of 1960 (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Fisk University Institute of Race Relations, 1957 (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Fraternal Order of Police (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Fundamentalism (Christian) (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Furman University (Box 49, Folder 14-15)
  - Ginter Park P.T.A., 1962-1966 (Box 49, Folder 16)
  - Grassroots Ecumenism program materials (Box 49, Folder 17)
  - Greek Orthodox (Box 49, Folder 18)
  - Holocaust studies (Box 50, Folder 1-2)
  - Homosexuality (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Housing (fair/open) (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Housing Opportunities Made Equal (H.O.M.E.) (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Institute for American Democracy (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Institute on Social Change in a Democratic Society, 1965 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Inter-Commission Committee on the Problems of Integration and Education in Community Life, 24-25 November 1958 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Intercultural education (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Interfaith relations (Box 50, Folder 10-11)
  - Intergroup education (Box 50, Folder 12-13)
  - Intergroup education, cont'd. (Box 51, Folder 1-8)
  - Intergroup relations (Box 51, Folder 9-10)
  - Intergroup relations, cont'd. (Box 52, Folder 1-9)
  - International Council of Christians and Jews (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - Islam (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - Israel, Jews, and Judaism (Box 52, Folder 12)
  - Israel, Jews, and Judaism, cont'd. (Box 53, Folder 1-4)
  - Jewish-Christian relations (Box 53, Folder 5-8)
  - Jewish organizations, publications (Box 53, Folder 9-10)
  - Johnstown, Ohio (Box 53, Folder 11-12)
  - Key 73 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Ku Klux Klan (Box 54, Folder 2-3)
  - May, Irving (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Mayor's Friendly Relations Committee (Charlotte, N.C.) (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - McIntire, Carl (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Memoirs (Peter Mellette) (Box 54, Folder 7-8)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 54, Folder 9-14)
  - Miscellaneous, cont'd. (Box 55, Folder 1-2)
  - Miscellaneous course materials and writing assignments (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous objects (Box 78)
    Objects include a medal featuring the name of the National Conference of Christians and Jews, the word "Brotherhood," and an outline map of the world; a cardboard cutout showing a cartoon man and a message supporting civil defense, and a school calendar noting religious holidays for 1954-1955. Also included is a medal-like object with a relief image of a man (possibly a Biblical figure) and another man with angel wings who appears to be crying over a book that is open to a page with "1938" written on it. The reverse is engraved to read "In the union of faiths we are fortified to serve mankind."
  - Miscellaneous organizations and programs (Box 55, Folder 4-10)
  - Moll, William J. (Box 55, Folder 11)
  - Morton, Sidney G. (Box 55, Folder 12)
  - National Association of Intergroup Officials (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - National Conference for Religious Freedom, 23-24 October 1986 (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - NCCJ and race issues (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - NCCJ meeting with President Kennedy, 21 November 1961 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - NCCJ response to bombings of religious buildings, 1958, 1960 (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Nelson, Claude D. (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Northside Community Council / Northside Community Association (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Notes (Box 56, Folder 8-12)
  - Obituary and eulogy notes for Peter Mellette, 1993 (Box 56, Folder 13)
  - Ohef Sholom Temple (Norfolk, Va.) bulletins, 1965-1979 (Box 56, Folder 14)
  - One Nation Under God: A Report on Our Moral and Spiritual Resources for Brotherhood, 10 November 1954 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Operation Metropolitan - Chicago Project 1956 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Our Moral and Spiritual Resources for International Cooperation, Reinhold Neibuhr, 1956 (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Personal travel (Box 57, Folder 4-5)
  - Photographs (Box 57, Folder 6)
    See also an oversize group photograph (rolled) taken at the National Staff Conference, 9 January 1967. Located in Series VII.
  - Planned Parenthood (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Prayers (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Prejudice (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - President's Committee on Government Contracts (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - Problems in the Economic and Social History of the U.S. course (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - Protestant (miscellaneous) (Box 57, Folder 12)
  - Psychology of Social Change course, Columbia University, 1950 (Box 57, Folder 13)
  - Quality Integrated Education Conference, 1972 (Box 57, Folder 14)
  - Race (Box 57, Folder 15)
  - Racism (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Real Estate Committee (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Religion and Education in a Pluralistic Society: A Discussion Guide and Resource Book, 1961 (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Religion and Freedom, 1958 (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Religion and public education (Box 58, Folder 5-8)
  - Religion and traffic safety (Box 58, Folder 9-10)
  - Religious discrimination in advertising legislation, 1952, 1954 (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Report of the National Advisory Commission on Civil Disorders, 1968 (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Richmond (Box 59, Folder 3-4)
  - Richmond Area Clergy Association (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Richmond Area Community Council / Richmond Area Safety Council (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Richmond Area Ministers Association (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - Richmond International Council (Box 59, Folder 8)
  - Richmond Public Schools (Box 59, Folder 9-10)
  - Richmond Urban League, 1956, 1967 (Box 59, Folder 11)
  - Rockwell, George L. (American Nazi Party) (Box 59, Folder 12)
  - Rotary Club (Box 59, Folder 13-14)
  - Rotary Club, cont'd. (Box 60, Folder 1-4)
  - Rotary Club: U.S. - Canada Exchange, 1977 (Box 60, Folder 5-6)
  - School desegregation (Box 60, Folder 7-10)
  - School desegregation, cont'd. (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Sharon High School (Sharon, S.C.) c/o 1936 reunion, 1986 (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Social Science Conference, 2-3 November 1966 (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Soviet Jewry (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Special Report of the National Task Force on Fiscal Responsibility, 27 April 1979 (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Speeches (Box 61, Folder 6-12)
  - Speeches, cont'd. (Box 62, Folder 1-9)
  - Speeches, cont'd. (Box 63, Folder 1-6)
  - Speed Memorial Church (Speed, Ind.) (Box 63, Folder 7-9)
  - Torch Club of Richmond (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - Travel (Box 64, Folder 1-2)
  - Unitarian (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - United Way (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - U.Va. Institute of Public Affairs, 1952-1953 (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - Urban issues (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - VCU conferences on urban education, 1969-1970 (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - Vickery, William E. (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - Virginia Congress of Parents and Teachers (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - Virginia Council on Human Relations (Box 64, Folder 10)
  - Virginia Operational Survival Plan (Box 64, Folder 11-12)
  - Virginia Retail Merchants Association Award, 1960 (Box 64, Folder 13)
  - Virginia/Richmond Area Committee for Public Schools (Box 64, Folder 14)
  - The Virginian (Box 65, Folder 1-2)
  - Watkins Glen, N. Y. (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Welfare (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - White House Conference on Children and Youth, 1970 (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - Wills (Peter and Susan Mellette) (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - Women (Box 65, Folder 7)
  - Women in Religion, 1941 (Box 65, Folder 8)
  - Working with Religious Groups, Clarence Wagner, 1947 (Box 65, Folder 9)
  - World Brotherhood (Box 65, Folder 10-11)
  - World hunger (Box 65, Folder 12-14)
- Series V. NCCJ financial papers, 1945-1982., Extent: 7 boxes. (Box 66-72)
  Miscellaneous financial papers include audit reports, budget projections and requests, and financial statements. Papers reflecting the NCCJ's fundraising include solicitation and thank-you letters, prospect lists, Special Gifts Committee correspondence, and a 1961 fundraising manual. A great deal of fundraising was done by means of awards dinners. Materials related to these events can be found in Series III.
  - Financial papers, 1945 (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Financial papers, 1946 (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Financial papers, 1947 (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Financial papers, 1948-1949 (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - Financial papers, 1950-1954 (Box 66, Folder 5)
  - Financial papers, 1955-1959 (Box 66, Folder 6)
  - Financial papers, 1960-1963 (Box 66, Folder 7)
  - Financial papers, 1964-1966 (Box 66, Folder 8)
  - Financial papers, 1967-1968 (Box 66, Folder 9)
  - Financial papers, 1969-1971 (Box 66, Folder 10)
  - Financial papers, 1972-1973 (Box 66, Folder 11)
  - Financial papers, 1974 (Box 66, Folder 12)
  - Financial papers, 1975 (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Financial papers, 1976 (Box 67, Folder 2-4)
  - Financial papers, 1977 (Box 67, Folder 5-8)
  - Financial papers, 1978 (Box 67, Folder 9-12)
  - Financial papers, 1978, cont'd. (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Financial papers, 1979 (Box 68, Folder 2-3)
  - Financial papers, 1980-1982 (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - Fundraising, 1946-1949 (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Fundraising, 1950 (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - Fundraising, 1951-1952 (Box 68, Folder 7)
  - Fundraising, 1953 (Box 68, Folder 8)
  - Fundraising, 1954 (Box 68, Folder 9-11)
  - Fundraising, 1955 (Box 68, Folder 12)
  - Fundraising, 1956 (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - Fundraising, 1957 (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - Fundraising, 1958 (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - Fundraising, 1959 (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - Fundraising, 1960 (Box 69, Folder 5-7)
  - Fundraising manual: Building Financial Support, 1961 (Box 69, Folder 8)
  - Fundraising, 1961 (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - Fundraising, 1962 (Box 70, Folder 2-6)
  - Fundraising, 1963 (Box 70, Folder 7)
  - Fundraising, 1964 (Box 70, Folder 8-9)
  - Fundraising, 1964, cont'd. (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - Fundraising, 1965 (Box 71, Folder 2-4)
  - Fundraising, 1966 (Box 71, Folder 5-6)
  - Fundraising, 1967 (Box 71, Folder 7)
  - Fundraising, 1968-1969 (Box 71, Folder 8)
  - Fundraising, 1970-1979 (Box 71, Folder 9)
  - Fundraising, undated (Box 71, Folder 10)
  - Fundraising, undated, cont'd. (Box 72, Folder 1-2)
- Series VI. Clippings and magazines, 1945-1993., Extent: 6 boxes. (Box 72-77)
  Mellette kept an extensive collection of clippings from various newspapers and magazines, as well as complete issues of several newsletters and magazines. Topics reflected in the clippings closely mirror the interests he demonstrated in other areas of his life: religion, interreligious and interracial relations, education, and social justice causes.
  - America (Box 72, Folder 3)
  - The Christian Century (Box 72, Folder 4-7)
  - Commonweal (Box 72, Folder 8)
  - Keeping the Dream Alive column, Don McElroy (Box 72, Folder 9)
  - Magazine/journal clippings, 1945-1992 (Box 72, Folder 10)
  - Magazine/journal clippings, undated (Box 72, Folder 11)
  - Magazines/journals, 1950's (Box 73, Folder 1-3)
  - Magazines/journals, 1960's (Box 73, Folder 4-5)
  - Magazines/journals, 1970's (Box 73, Folder 6-7)
  - Magazines/journals, 1980's (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - NCCJ reprints of journal/newspaper articles (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - The New Republic (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, 1940's-1960's (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, 1970's (Box 74, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters, 1980's (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper clippings (photocopies and reprints) (Box 74, Folder 7)
  - Presbyterian Outlook (Box 74, Folder 8)
  - The Religious Herald (Box 74, Folder 9)
  - Reprints distributed by Community Relations Service/American Jewish Committee (Box 74, Folder 10)
  - Saturday Review (Box 74, Folder 11-12)
  - Southern School News (Box 74, Folder 13)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1946-1959 (Box 75)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1960-1969 (Box 76)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1970-1993 and undated (Box 77)